mymathlab.com 2010-02-08

# Pearson Education: Privacy Policy

ONLINE PRIVACY STATEMENT

PLEASE READ THE FOLLOWING CAREFULLY

GENERAL INFORMATION ABOUT THE POLICY OF THIS WEBSITE IN ITS COLLECTION, PROTECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF THE PERSONAL INFORMATION GATHERED ON THIS SITE. IF YOU ARE UNDER 18 YEARS OF AGE, PLEASE BE SURE TO READ THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT WITH YOUR PARENTS OR GUARDIAN AND ASK THEM QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.

This website, Pearsoned.com (the "Site"), is owned and operated by Pearson Education, Inc.. ("Pearson"). Pearson recognizes the importance of explaining our privacy policies to users of our Site and protecting the privacy of Personally Identifiable Information we obtain through the site. Please note that this Privacy Statement may be revised by Pearson from time to time, particularly to address changes in our business, the law or technology. If that happens, we will post the revised policy here. Revisions are effective upon posting and your continued use of this Site after the posting will be subject to the changed terms of the revisions.

**LINKS TO OTHER SITES**

Links from this site can take you to the sites of several divisions of Pearson -- SCHOOL, HIGHER ED, PROFESSIONAL, GLOBAL -- as well as to third party websites or resources. The information practices of third party websites are not covered by this Privacy Statement or any other policies or terms of this Site. The sites of each of our divisions may also have a different privacy policy and terms of use. Be sure that you know the terms of use and privacy policy of any linked website before using it.

**WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND USE**

We consider the following to be examples of Personally Identifiable Information but there may be others: your first and last name, email address, home address, phone number, date of birth, credit card information, and certain other information, such as a Social Security Number, if it is linked with your Personally Identifiable Information. We strongly recommend that you not use your Social Security Number or any other important ID as a user ID or password for this Site or others.

Pearson Education does not collect Personally Identifiable Information about a user, unless it is voluntarily provided to our Company and so that we can serve the user's needs and our legitimate business purposes as stated here. For example, when the user sends us a message or makes an online purchase, we need to retain certain Personally Identifiable Information on this Site in order to respond. A user's Personally Identifiable Information may also be used by our company to help us improve this Site, and for our company's marketing and promotional purposes. The information will be treated confidentially within our company, as we protect other confidential information. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features.

**PUBLIC POSTINGS**

Users should be reminded that any Personally Identifiable Information that is voluntarily posted by a user to a public area of a Pearson Education Web site (for example, a posting to a bulletin board or chat room) might be collected and used by others. We cannot prevent such uses.

**INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE**

Except as specifically stated in this statement, our policy is not to share the Personally Identifiable Information collected through this Site with third parties, but we may share this Personally Identifiable Information with affiliates of Pearson, and other companies and organizations who perform work for us under contract or sell products or services that complement our products and services. We also may disclose Personally Identifiable Information (a) in response to a subpoena, court order or legal process, to the extent permitted and required by law; (b) to protect user security or the security of other persons, consistent with applicable laws; (c) in connection with a sale, joint venture or other transfer to some or all of Pearson or the assets of Pearson; or (d) in order to enforce the Site's Terms of Use. We exercise commercially reasonable care otherwise not to share, disclose or sell the Personally Identifiable Information of users to third-parties, except with the prior approval of the user. 

Pearson may use a third party service to collect anonymous visitor information like IP addresses, browser types (such as Internet Explorer or Netscape), referring pages, pages visited and time spent on a particular site. Pearson collects this information (1) for statistical analysis of web page traffic patterns; (2) to administer our Site and servers; (3) to allow for auditing of our services by some third parties who have that right; and (4) for internal purposes to make marketing decisions.

For "course management sites" that provide materials and services to instructors and students for purposes of specific courses or testing, the site may display the names, email addresses, grades and log-in names in instructor grade books and make them available to school administrators. Instructors can use student email addresses for communication with students regarding the course and administrators may store personal data generated by the course site tools for the purpose of maintaining educational records or other legitimate educational purposes.

**SPECIAL NOTICE TO PARENTS, TEACHERS AND CHILDREN**

**PARENTS AND TEACHERS:** We encourage parents, guardians and teachers to spend time with their Children (Children 12 and under) when their Children engage in the on-line activities on this Site. We will never request Personally Identifiable Information from a Child in any of our public postings areas. We do not require a Child to disclose more Personally Identifiable Information, than is reasonably necessary to participate in the on-line activity. .No Personally Identifiable Information of children should be submitted to or posted on this Site by Children without the consent of their parent or guardian. We encourage parents to help us protect their Children's privacy by instructing them never to provide Personally Identifiable Information on this Site or any other website without parental permission.

**CHILDREN:** Please do not give your full name, email address, home address, telephone number or any other Personally Identifiable Information that would enable someone to contact you either on-line or off-line, without first asking your parent or guardian and teacher for permission.

We do not knowingly collect Personally Identifiable Information from Children on this Site either directly or passively except when a Child may voluntarily submit such information through a "[Contact Us](http://www.pearsonschool.com/index.cfm?locator=PSZ3Yk&level=CUForm)" link on the Site or a public posting area on the Site, if such feature is available. If a Child e-mails us via a "[Contact Us](http://www.pearsonschool.com/index.cfm?locator=PSZ3Yk&level=CUForm)" link on any child-directed area of this Site and we can identify the sender as a Child, any Personally Identifiable Information submitted will only be used to respond on a one-time basis to such Child. In addition, if we have actual knowledge that a Child is sending or posting Personally Identifiable Information on any area of this Site, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete such Personally Identifiable Information before it is made public. Please note that any online store that may be accessed from the Site is intended for parents, teachers and other adult purchasers over the age of 18 and requires the submission of Personally Identifiable Information to fulfill and service any transactions.

We may disclose a Child's Personally Identifiable Information if we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property, other users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. We may also disclose a Child's Personally Identifiable Information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

**COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION FROM COOKIES**

Our Site uses "cookies" to obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses the Site, Cookies are textual identifiers that our systems transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our Site to recognize your browser, and to optimize and sometimes custimize your use of our Site. If you want to disable cookies, you can. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers and "add-on" programs will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. It is your choice, but cookies allow you to take full advantage of this Site's features, and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

We do not use cookies to get users' Personally Identifiable Information before a user registers with our Site and affirmatively opts-in. Once a user opts-in and and provides personal information for purposes of receiving more information from us, we do collect and use that information obtained through the cookie technology for purposes of marketing to you, in accordance with this policy. If you do not want to receive e-mail or other marketing communications from us, you can opt out of further marketing to the addresses you have provided.

In connection with cookies we may use web beacons to track response rates to certain email communications that a user has opted to receive from us. If a user has registered with our Site, we may collect certain personal information in connection with the web beacon including the referring email address. This information is not shared with third parties. 

Pearson reserves the right to monitor your use of the site to determine if you are complying with our terms and the right, in its sole discretion, to terminate your access to the Site,

**OBTAINING ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ABOUT PRIVACY**

If you have any concerns or questions about privacy on this Site, please [Contact Us](http://www.pearsonschool.com/index.cfm?locator=PSZ3Yk&level=CUForm).  
(Revised -June, 2007)  
Pearson Education, Inc., One Lake Street, Upper Saddle River, New Jersey 07458.
